<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tomas Diez on Tomas Diez</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tomas Diez on Tomas Diez</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 15:09:13 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>/posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 15:09:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tomas Diez is a Venezuelan Urbanist specialized in digital fabrication and its implications in the future of cities and society. He is co-founder of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fablabbcn.org&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Fab Lab Barcelona&lt;/a&gt; at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.iaac.net&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Institute for Advanced Architecture of Catalonia (IAAC)&lt;/a&gt;, the director of the Fab City Research Laboratory, and director of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://mdef.iaac.net&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Master in Design for Emergent Futures&lt;/a&gt;. He leads the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fab.city&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Fab City Global Initiative&lt;/a&gt; in collaboration with an international team of thinkers and makers, and the European project manager for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fabfoundation.org&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Fab Foundation&lt;/a&gt;. Tomas holds a Bachelor degree in Urban Planning and Sociology by the University Simon Bolivar (Caracas - Venezuela), a Diploma in social work at the University of La Havana (Cuba), a Master in Advanced Architecture by IAAC, and a Diploma in Digital Fabrication from a pilot program to kickstart the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fabacademy.org&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Fab Academy&lt;/a&gt; by completing the class “How to Make Almost Anything”, offered by MIT&amp;rsquo;s Center for Bits and Atoms in 2008. He works as a close collaborator in the development of the Fab Lab Network together with MIT and the Fab Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomas co-founded the Exploring Emergent Futures platform in the Design Products department at the Royal College of Arts in London, and is co-founder of initiatives such as: the crowdsensing platform &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.smartcitizen.me&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Smart Citizen&lt;/a&gt;, the social network &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fablabs.io&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;FabLabs.io&lt;/a&gt;, and the artist residency &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.studiop52.com&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;StudioP52&lt;/a&gt;; he has been the organiser and co-chair of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fab10.org&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;FAB10 Barcelona&lt;/a&gt;, the 10th international fab lab conference and annual meeting hosted by Fab Lab Barcelona (IAAC) in 2014. Tomas has been appointed by The Guardian and Nesta as one of the top 10 digital social innovators to watch in 2013, and has been awarded by the Catalan ICT association as the entrepreneur of the year in 2014. His research interests relate to the use of digital fabrication tools to transform reality, and how the use of new technologies can change the way people consume, produce and relate with each other in cities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Short:
Tomas Diez is a Venezuelan Urbanist specialized in digital fabrication and its implications on the future cities and society. He is the co-founder and director of Fab Lab Barcelona at the Institute for Advanced Architecture of Catalonia (IAAC), and is a founding partner of the Fab City Global Initiative. He is also the director of the recently launched Master in Design for Emergent Futures at IAAC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add to short as optional:
Tomas has been appointed by The Guardian and Nesta as one of the top 10 digital social innovators to watch in 2013, and has been awarded by the Catalan ICT association as the entrepreneur of the year in 2014. His research interests relate to the use of digital fabrication tools to transform reality, and how the use of new technologies can change the way people consume, produce and relate with each other in cities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photos: &lt;a href=&#34;https://images.adsttc.com/media/images/598e/1d04/b22e/382f/f400/0056/medium_jpg/Tomas_Diez_Fab_Lab.jpg?1502485761&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Profile 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Profile 2](&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1HB85s434bTWpI4ulsGd39z7iXB35OBGP/view?usp=sharing]&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1HB85s434bTWpI4ulsGd39z7iXB35OBGP/view?usp=sharing]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/draftone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/draftone/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
